So which other change can we implement? Let's have a look at our layout component, in the layout folder
Peki hangi ortalama deiimi uygulayabiliriz Dzende klasre ve bileenlere bakalm,
under components. If we have a look at it, it's clearly a class based component and it has a state, a state
ona bakarsak aka snf temelli bir bileen ve karar alc
to handle their display of the sideDrawer.
grntsn ele alan bir eyalete sahiptir.
Now I don't really consider it to be a container, though you could argue for it to be one because obviously
Akas baka bileenler ierdiinden ve devletleri onlara braktndan, onu gerekten bir konteyner
it contains some other components and it passes states down to them,
olarak grmyorum, ancak bir konteyner olduunu iddia edebildiniz.
so it wouldn't necessarily be wrong to place that layout component here in their containers folder
Dolaysyla, bileenlerinin burada kendi kapsayc klasrlerine yerletirilmesi yanl
like this
olmayabilir.
so now I'll move it over there.
imdi de oraya hareket ettir.
You could also argue for something different with the given folder structure which of course is only
Ayrca verilen klasr yaps ile farkl bir ey dnebilirsin ki bu tabii
just one possible way where I have this hoc folder for higher order components,
ki daha yksek sipari bileenleri iin bu eski klasr kullanabildiim tek olas yol budur.
you could kind of argue that a layout is really just a higher order component,
Bir dzenin gerekten sadece daha yksek bir dzen bileeninin olduunu iddia edebilirsin.
because what you're doing with it is you're wrapping your other components with the layout.
nk onunla yaptnz ey, ortalama bileenlerini dzen ile sarmalsnz.
So the burger builder component in our application but once we add routing, that of course are going to
Yani burger Bolar bileeni uygulamamzda ancak bir kez bir ynlendirme ekledik ki elbette daha
be more components.
fazla bileen olacak.
And in the app.js folder, we're really just wrapping the burger builder with our layout component
Gerekten de daha dolgun bir hal alyor, aslnda burger yapcy katmanl bileeni ile saryoruz.
and this essentially makes it a higher order component.
Ve bu aslnda daha yksek bir dzen bileen yapar.
These are maybe just semantics,
Bunlar belki sadece semantik.
it doesn't really change the way your application work, how you call your components.
Uygulamanzn bileenlerini nasl ifade ettiini gerekten de deitirmez.
Still you could move layout into containers or you could move it into hoc or maybe in your application,
Yine de izin verilen konteynrlara yerletirebilir veya H O C'ye veya belki uygulamanzda tayabilirsiniz.
you don't really have a hoc folder,
Gerekten bir HELOC klasr yok.
maybe there, you just have containers and components.
Belki orada sadece konteynrlar ve paralar var.
There is more than one correct way,
Birden fazla doru yol var.
now I like this set up though where layout is now in the hoc folder because I consider it a higher
imdi, dzeni H O C klasrnde olduu halde, daha yksek bir sipari bileeni olarak grdm
order component,
iin kurmay seviyorum.
it's only there to wrap other components and therefore here we're using it in app.js to wrap whichever
Yalnzca Abra bileenlerini sarmak iin var ve bu nedenle buray kullanyoruz ve hangi yoldan rotamz sardmz iin
route we're rendering
app aptest uyguluyoruz.
hence I move it into the hoc folder.
Dolaysyla onu HLC klasrne tadm.
Now I will also create a new subfolder in hoc
imdi de HUAC'de alt klasr kullanacam ve kullanacam.
therefore, the aux folder and move my aux.js file in there.
Bu nedenle yaylar klasr ve arklarm kovalamaca kovalamam sala.
Now this of course will lead to some errors because now we will have some import issues. In the layout
imdi elbette baz hatalara yol aacaktr, nk u anda mizanpaj klasrndeki baz ie aktarma sorunlaryla
folder, we'll need to adjust our imports to still have correct paths to all the components we depend
ithalatlarmz, baml olduumuz tm bileenlere gre doru pauvr'lara sahip olmalar iin ayarlamamz gerekecek
on and we'll have to make sure that wherever we're importing aux, we also adjust the path.
ve bizden emin olmanz gerekir; POF'yi de ayarladmz Oxx' ie aktaryoruz.
So let's quickly do that,
Hadi abucak balayalm.
I'll start the layout component and I'll start with the aux import since layout is hoc and aux's,
Dzen bileenini balatacam ve Laodicea HAMC ve oxes'tan bu yana alks ithalatyla balayacam.
we only have to go up one level now to go into the hoc folder, so we can remove that part
AOC klasrne girmek iin yalnzca bir seviye yukar kmamz gerekiyor, bylece o ksm kaldrabiliriz.
we already are in there and then move into the aux folder and then import the aux.js file,
Zaten oradayz ve daha sonra alks klasrne getikten sonra ox paylamlarn indiriyoruz.
so this is how we need to adjust this.
Yani bunu ayarlamamz gereken tek ey bu.
The classes import doesn't change of course because there's css files in the same folder but the toolbar
ayn klasrde olduu kadar hzl ancak ara ubuu ie aktarm deimiyor ve
import does change, there we need to go all the way up then into the components folder and then we
bileen klasrne kadar her yere gitmemiz gerekiyor ve ardndan navigasyon klasrne gidebiliriz ve Temel
can go into the navigation folder and I can basically copy that part here prior to navigation from the
olarak, bu blm buradaki gezi ncesi ara ubuundan kopyalayabilir ve burada da yan ekmece iin kullanabilirsiniz.
toolbar import and also use it here for the sideDrawer.
Klaas'n ieri aktarm tabii ki deimez, nk bu
So with that, the layout component is updated,
Bylece, dzen bileeni gncellenir.
Now what I also do is I need to restart and give a start because it seems to break on that aux file
imdi ne yaptm, yeniden balatmam gerekiyor ve insanlar balamal nk grnmemesi gereken eyleri
which it really shouldn't,
kryor gibi grnyor.
but we'll probably also get some other errors here because we're importing aux
Ancak Oxx'u ie aktaracamz iin muhtemelen baka oklar da alacaz.
in other files. In the app.js file,
Aslnda Arafat'n elinde.
we also need to adjust the import for the layout component
Hepimizin bir dzen bileeninin ie aktarmn ayarlamamz gerekiyor.
it's of course now in the hoc folder,
Elbette u anda HAMC klasrndedir.
so that is something we should adjust.
Bu yzden ayarlamamz gereken bir ey.
Then in the burger builder as you can see here in the error message, we got to an error because there
Daha sonra Bergere Boulder'da, aero mesajnda grebileceiniz gibi Bergere Boulder'da
in the burger builder we are of course using the aux component.
olduklar iin bir hata yaptk, elbette kz bileenini kullanyoruz.
So there we need to adjust the import because now it's essentially still in the hoc folder
Dolaysyla, ie aktarm ayarlamamz gerekiyor, nk imdi esasen HLC klasrnde.
but we created that aux subfolder which we need to adjust. In the sideDrawer component, there
Ancak ayarlamanz gereken alks alt klasrn yan izimde veya orada bileen oluturduk.
we also are using aux and there we also have to go to the aux folder and import the aux.js file from
Ayrca Oxx' kullanyoruz ve oradaki ox klasrne gidip oradaki dosyay ie
there. In the modal component which is in the UI folder, there we also use aux
aktarmalyz; buradaki modal bileeni UI klasrnde var, biz de alks kullanyoruz.
so we also need to add slash aux at the end here, and in the order summary, we face a similar issue,
Bu yzden sonunda burada arpma iaretleri eklemeliyiz ve sipari zetinde de benzer bir sorunla kar karyayz.
there we also need to import the aux file from within the aux folder
Orada kutu klasrnden kz dn de almamz gerek.
and with all these changes, now we should have a working application again.
Ve imdi tm bu deiikliklerle yeniden bir alma bavurusu yapmalyz.
Let's quickly check if it does work,
e yarayp yarayp yaramadna hzl bir ekilde gz atalm.
it's looking good.
yi grnyor.
So now we got an application which works again without throwing any errors
imdi hatalar atmadan tekrar alan bir uygulama aldk.
but now with our new folder structure, which is optional but which makes more sense in my opinion since
Fakat imdi opsiyonel olan, ancak bence daha mantkl olan yeni klasr yapmzla, bileenlerin
or due to the way our components do work. Now with that, we really have a great application,
u an iin nasl ilediinden dolay gerekten harika bir uygulamanz var.
let's now move on with this course.
imdi bu kursla devam edelim.